You are
extraordinary, my sons.
Unlike anything
the world has ever seen.
Bound for greatness.
Destined to protect
the people of New York.
A dark force is growing.
A criminal organization
known as the Foot Clan.
So named
because they step over
the good people of this city
with no regard.
Their leader, The Shredder,
will come at you
with ferocity.
His Foot Clan
will outnumber you.
The people of New York
will look upon you
as their only hope.
Eyes focused.
Elbows locked.
Stance low.
And we begin.
Be one with the blades.
Lead their path.
I know you are eager
to answer their calls,
but your training
is not yet complete.
The world below
must remain your home.
As your father,
you must trust me.
Patience.
You're not yet ready
to go above ground.
But I believe
when that day comes
and you rise to the streets,
you are going to be
responsible
for amazing things.
Mr. Rivetti!
Mr. Rivetti.
Mr. Rivetti, please.
You're the most
persistent human
I've ever met in my life,
I swear.
Look, I already told the cops
everything, all right?
But maybe there's a detail
you could've forgotten
to share with the police.
Sweetheart, you don't forget
something like that.
Ten guys storm in here,
broad daylight,
force us to the ground
at gunpoint.
And these are
restricted chemicals.
Benzyl cyanide and some
deaminating agents, too.
You don't just buy this stuff,
even on the black market.
Wait, you said
deaminating agents,
those are used
in genetic research.
Is there anybody else
that's trafficking these
sort of chemicals besides you?
There's one other
high-security facility
along this waterfront.
But they don't move
nearly as much cargo as we do.
O'Neil! We're live
in 30 minutes! Come on!
Uh... No, no, no,
I'll be right back.
Please don't go anywhere.
Come on, you're killing me.
I'm working.
That's a paying job?
No.
Because we have
an actual paying job.
Look, you don't think that
every crime reporter
in the city has been trying to
work this Foot Clan story?
I know that, but there is
a new angle on this,
and I am this close
to getting it.
I just need
a couple of more...
Let's just stick
to what we're good at.
Let's stick to what we're
good at. We're good at it.
In five, four...
Hi, guys, this is April O'Neil
from Channel 6 News
and I am here
in beautiful New York City
on the first day of spring.
And you know what that means.
It is time to shed
that pesky winter weight.
And here with me today
is celebrity fitness trainer
Harley Pasternak. Hi, Harley.
Good morning, April.
Twenty years I've studied
the animal kingdom.
There are fat pigs,
there are fat cows.
There are no fat birds.
All right, I want you
to visualize a sexy seagull.
So we're going to squat down
and flap your wings.
Right over there.
Full extension.
Picture you're leaving
the cold north
and you're flying.
You're migrating.
Four years of journalism
school so that I can do that.
Four years of my life, Vern.
It's embarrassing.
Look, O'Neil, I get it,
you want to be
a serious journalist.
I see you sniffing around
the newsroom
for the big stories.
But it's also okay
to just give people something
a little lighter.
A little... Little froth.
Froth?
You know, how,
when you get a coffee,
it's just, like, coffee,
then they put a little froth
on it. It's kind of nice.
Vern, that's foam.
Yes, foam, froth,
you get the point.
It's just... It's nice,
it tastes good, it's candy.
You ever heard the expression,
"Never take candy
from a baby"?
It's because
even babies love candy!
It's nice.
And you're giving people
something they like
that's good and nice.
They look at you and they see,
"Wow, there's a nice...
There's...
"...candy."
The point is, I think that
you should be rewarded,
not punishing yourself. Okay?
And I'm...
I'm prepared to reward you.
I say that we go to my buddy's
old restaurant downtown.
It's very vibey...
We just ate
on the way over here.
No, I know we just...
I'm not saying
for a full meal, we're just
gonna eat appeteasers.
I got to go
finish that interview.
I'll see you
at the office, Vern!
I will see you at the office!
I just wanted
to follow up, Mr. Rivetti.
Are you kidding me?
How did you get my number?
Listen, I already told you
everything I know
about this crime, everything.
Okay, you wanna know
anything else,
you go back down to the docks
and you see
my guy Stan. He'll tell you
anything else
you need to know, okay?
And hey, do me a favor.
Lose my number, all right?
Good.
It's clear.
Let's open it up.
Container's good.
Move on to the next one.
Move it out!
Get those to the trucks now!
Move out,
next point! Go, go, go.
Channel 6.
Chris.
Chris, it's April.
I'm at the docks.
Whatever you got
can wait for tomorrow.
No, no, I need...
2-3-2, clear!
- Get it out of my way.
- Copy that.
Damn it.
Unit two, area three, move!
I've got movement!
Keep your eyes over here!
Weapons free!
Hold position!
Retreat! Retreat!
Get out of here!
Taylor. Taylor!
Hey. I'm Skyping with my mom.
You have no idea
what I just went through.
I am freaking out.
I saw a Foot Clan attack.
Are you okay?
I was riding my bike
by the docks.
It was night,
it's dark already
and there are
Foot Clan soldiers everywhere.
Then out of nowhere,
there was this guy
fighting back against them.
And he...
He left behind this symbol.
And I know
that I've seen it before.
I can't remember where.
But there is someone
fighting back
against the Foot Clan.
There is a vigilante
in this city.
And no one knows, but I do.
I know.
And now I have my story.
There is no more
froth and foam for me.
What?
Never mind.
All right, we need a lead
for tonight. Who's got it?
"Major redevelopments proposed
"for lower Manhattan."
No.
I got something.
"NYPD task force taking credit
"for small decline
in Foot-related crime."
I like that.
Let's run with that.
Yes, ma'am.
7:00 AM broadcast,
we have three minutes to air.
Oh, O'Neil.
I'll talk to you in a minute.
I know that I'm actually
overstepping
my boundaries by being here,
but I think that you're gonna
I actually think that you're
all gonna want to hear
what I have to say.
Um, I witnessed
an attempted Foot Clan robbery
at the docks
in Brooklyn last night.
Hold on, the scanner said
that gunshots were heard,
but there were no reports
of any Foot Clan activity.
That's because
whatever they were
attempting to do was stopped.
What were you doing
in Brooklyn anyway?
Was there
a trampoline convention?
I was in Brooklyn
because I was reporting,
not sitting behind my desk,
McNaughton.
Okay, kids!
Who stopped it?
Well, there was this guy.
I didn't see him clearly,
but he was swinging
these giant
shipping containers
and knocking these guys
into the... Into the river.
There is a vigilante
that is fighting back
against the Foot Clan.
There's a huge story here!
O'Neil, I think you found
Superman. That's cool.
The vigilante is real.
I saw him.
O'Neil, I'm gonna assume
that you would not
come up here and tell us
this fantastic story
without some tangible proof.
I took this photo of one
of the shipping containers.
I actually think that
it may be his calling card.
This is nothing,
O'Neil. This is nothing!
That's exactly the point.
Somebody
stopped a Foot robbery
and left no evidence.
There is nothing.
Oh, I get it.
You wanted me to put "nothing"
on the nightly news.
Of course not.
You know, I'm gonna pretend we
never had this conversation.
I'm erasing it from my mind.
And the rest of us,
we're gonna go back to work.
Let's hit it!
Hello, everybody.
Welcome to the Channel 6
Morning News.
New developments in that
ongoing sanitation strike
to tell you about.
But first,
after reviewing the city's
soaring crime rates
with the police commissioner,
Councilman Dan Gregor took
to the steps of City Hall,
reaffirming
the city's commitment
to fight against the rising
crime organization
calling themselves
the Foot Clan.
He did so on the heels
of a renewed
contract with Eric Sacks
and Sacks Industries.
Using the Sacks research
and securities technology,
this city greatly improves
its chances
of bringing the Foot Clan
to justice!
We couldn't have anticipated
the vigilante
showing up at the docks,
Master Shredder.
But we've never seen
an enemy like this.
Their size.
Their strength.
They're not human.
I don't believe
in fairy tales.
It's what society wants
to reduce the Foot Clan to.
A myth.
But the Foot Clan
will rise again.
Capture the vigilantes
however you can.
Use innocent people as bait.
No one will stop us
in our quest
to reclaim victory.
We will own this city.
Ladies
and gentlemen, please join me
in welcoming
the NYPD's top benefactor,
Eric Sacks.
Please, please. Please.
Sit down, sit down.
I have to say,
it's wonderful to see so many
people out here tonight,
especially in a neighborhood
so hard hit
by the Foot's crime wave.
Years ago, my life
was touched by tragedy.
I was a young scientist
working with
a world-class team
on cutting-edge research.
And our laboratory
was attacked,
set fire to, robbed,
by the cowards that
call themselves the Foot Clan.
Several of my employees
lost their lives that day.
And it is in their honor,
in their memory,
that Sacks Industries,
whether through Sacks Biomed,
Sacks Robotics
or Sacks Construction,
to keeping the city
of New York, our city,
safe.
So whenever someone
takes flame to this city,
I will be there
to put the fire out.
And that's a promise.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Great work, sir.
Very inspirational.
Mr. Sacks. April O'Neil.
You worked with my father.
Oh!
I can't believe it.
I haven't seen you since...
Since his funeral.
It was a long time ago.
Yeah.
I just wanted to tell you
that your words
really resonated with me,
and I hope to one day
contribute to the city
in the way that you do.
Well, it looks like you're
doing a pretty good job.
Channel 6, very impressive,
April.
Um... Thank you. It's, uh...
It isn't exactly everything
I anticipated it would be.
As long as you are
true to yourself,
your father will always
be proud of you.
Mr. Sacks, we have to be
uptown at 7:00.
I'll see you on TV.
Eric Sacks was
so inspiring.
I know this is a story
that actually matters.
The superhero one?
That's a good idea.
I should chase that down.
Where's everybody going?
- O'Neil! Where are you going?
- Hey.
April!
Hey!
What are you running from?
Wait, wait!
Shots fired,
Broadway and Centre Street.
Heavy Foot Clan activity
at the Broad Street platform.
But you know
we're not supposed
to go above ground.
We started something,
we gotta finish it.
This is insane.
That cat is playing  Chopsticks
with chopsticks!
Don't be an idiot.
- Aw.
- Okay.
Let's rock 'n' roll, boys!
Run!
Get out!
Go, go!
If you want to live, do it!
Go on!
Just stay down!
Get over here!
Keep moving!
Keep your
hands where I can see them!
Move to the side.
- They're bombs.
- Shut up!
On the ground!
Nobody move!
We know you're out there!
If you don't surrender,
we start executing hostages!
Get your
head down! Don't move!
Don't make me
tell you again! Not a word!
Don't look at me!
Don't! Don't do it!
You!
Stand up!
All aboard!
On your 12!
Come on!
That's right.
Like a shadow, bra.
Let's go!
Let's move!
Right here.
Some kind of freak!
There were a couple of them!
Whoo! Right past me!
They saved us.
Go, go, go!
Let's go, guys! Both sides!
Yeah, that's
what I'm talking about!
Yeah, boys, bring it in.
That was amazing.
You were incredible!
Great elbow, Donnie.
Oh, yeah!
That's what I'm talking about.
This is our city!
These are our streets!
You mess
with us, you step into
the Wu, whoo, Tang!
Ooh, yeah!
Did you see that guy's
jaw connect with the concrete?
He'll be drinking
out of a sippy cup for months!
Ah, that's what
I'm talking about, brothers.
Like shadows in the night.
Completely unseen.
It's a camera flash.
Who's behind the camera flash?
By my calculations,
it's a girl.
Give her some flowers,
earn her trust.
I got this.
Raph, no, no, no! Come on!
Give me the camera.
Ooh, look, he's
doing his Batman voice.
She's so hot, I can feel
my shell tightening.
We can hear you!
If you don't give me
the camera, I'm gonna...
Enough!
Back off, Raph.
I only saw Batman once!
Ma'am, hello. I apologize.
My colleague here
forgot to say "please."
So,
would you please
hand over the camera?
No, no, no, no. Whoa.
Whoa. Chill. It's just a mask.
See? Don't freak out.
Right?
Ah!
Oh, I think that went well.
Breathing steady.
Blood pressure stabilizing.
Why are we still here
playing doctor?
She may have a head injury.
Uh, correction.
She's a hot chick
who may have a head injury,
which makes it
- our civic duty to...
- Ma'am, ma'am.
Can you hear me? Do you know
what city you're in?
Do you know where you are?
Have you seen that video
where the cat
plays  Chopsticks
with the chopsticks?
Can we focus here?
Guys, please!
Come on. Give her some air.
What are you?
Well, Miss,
uh, we're ninjas.
We're mutants.
Well, technically,
we're turtles.
Oh, and we're teenagers!
But we can still have
adult conversations.
Wait, wait, wait. So...
You're...
Ninja, mutant,
turtle, teenagers?
Well, when you put it like
that, it sounds ridiculous!
See, she's looking at us
like we're freaks.
I bet that's why you took
our picture, wasn't it?
To show your friends?
Bro, that's a good thing!
Maybe she has hot friends.
Looking for this?
Don't break it.
No, no, no. Please.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
We don't break things,
we fix them.
Donnie already wiped
the phone, genius.
Problem solved, moving on.
And who put you in charge?
You know who did.
Ooh, tension! It's been like
30 whole minutes
since you guys
had this argument.
Leonardo, if we want
to make it home before Master,
we gotta hustle.
Leonardo?
Do not say a word
about this to anyone.
If you do, we will find you.
April O'Neil.
We're on the move, Raphael.
Raphael?
Yeah!
We'll find you, O'Neil.
I'm sorry, that came across
super creepy, okay?
We will find you, though.
I was on fire, bro!
Did you see me back there?
Guys, I totally
talked to a girl!
Shut up, Mikey!
Yeah, bra!
Mikey, was that you?
Pepperoni.
Leonardo. I know those
names. I know those names.
Raphael, Raphael. Leonardo.
Good evening.
This is April O'Neil,
reporting live
from my daddy's lab.
I know it sounds
pretty boring,
but actually, he does
some pretty cool stuff.
Time to put
the camera away, April.
Aw, Dad!
And now I will show you
something amazing.
It's supposed to be
from a different planet
in outer space!
Here we go.
Ah!
Mr. Sacks,
what sort of experiments
are you doing here?
Oh, that's
a very complicated question.
We're trying to change
the world.
Look at the camera!
Hello, Splinter.
And these are
my little turtles, Leonardo,
Raphael,
Michelangelo and Donatello.
The fans want to see you!
I knew it.
The vigilante, I saw him.
I saw them! I saw them.
I've known them
since I was a little girl.
They were my pets.
They were my childhood pets,
and they were named after
Italian Renaissance painters.
Mom, I want to move back home.
Is he here?
I don't see him.
Donnie?
My thermal scans indicate
there's a 74% variable
that there's
a 61% chance he's not...
That he's not here, guys.
That he's not here.
Okay.
Fall in, quietly.
Dude.
So, guys, if it wasn't already
obvious with that girl,
dibs.
If Master Splinter catches us,
he'll send us
back to the Ha'shi.
I ain't going back
to the Ha'shi.
Every time we're in the
Ha'shi, it's because of you.
Well, bro, you won't have
to worry about me
dragging you down anymore.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm going out on my own.
First chance I get.
How are we gonna finish our
hip-hop Christmas album, bro?
You're the hype man!
Shut up.
I got glop in my eye.
Shh! He's not going anywhere.
We all stick together.
Sorry I spit
in your eye, bro.
Shh!
Guys? Guys.
We got a bogey.
Uh...
Where have you been?
We weren't...
I forgot to soak my retainer!
I'm totally sleepwalking!
Look, Mikey's
sleeping and walking.
He's totally innocent.
Enough!
You disobeyed a direct order.
Why did you go above ground?
What happened?
Very well.
If that's how
it's going to be,
to the Ha'shi!
O'Neil! All right, what was so
important I had to get here?
Okay. Are you ready?
Yeah.
Okay.
You know how
I saw the vigilante?
Yeah.
But I had no photos
or evidence to show you,
so I just sounded crazy.
Yes.
Okay. But I saw him again.
Well, I didn't see him again,
I saw them,
because there's four.
There's not just one, there's
four. And I was standing
as close to them
as you are to me right now.
What'd they look like?
I'll show you.
What?
Like this.
Like turtles?
Well, they don't
look like turtles
because they are turtles.
They're over six feet tall
and they speak English.
Oh, my God.
I was awake all night, please
look, I was awake all night
googling all
of the thwarted crimes
over the past three months,
and this symbol
appeared at every single one.
Look!
Every single one of them.
This one, look.
Here, here, here, here, here.
And it's an ancient Japanese
symbol that means "family."
Wait, it's on my laptop.
I can't believe
you brought me in to do this!
It's here, it's here.
This is my father's lab.
This is the same lab
where these things were born
or created
or mutated.
Or, I don't know
the terminology,
but will you please
just look at what
I'm showing you and listen
to me. It's all connected.
The turtles are
the vigilantes
and the vigilantes
are these turtles.
Pizza has cheese,
tomato sauce,
all your favorite stuff.
Eat it. You guys need
nutrition. Or not.
I just want to be clear.
You are now telling me
that there are
four six-foot talking turtles
walking around New York City,
and no one has
seen them but you?
That's what I'm telling you.
I don't mean to laugh,
but is there anything else
we should know about them?
They're ninjas.
I'm sorry, what?
And they do karate.
Okay, get out.
O'Neil!
It could have been worse.
I just got fired, Vern.
How could it be worse?
Maybe it's good. Maybe you
should take a little time,
take care of yourself.
Come on,
let me give you a ride.
Not unless you're going
to the Eric Sacks estate.
April... Hey!
I'm not giving up
on this story.
You gotta put that to bed.
Would all of those
other great reporters
that you worked with, would
they have "put it to bed"?
No. That's different.
How is it different?
They all started exactly
where I am, right?
I'm not driving the
Channel 6 news van
onto the Sacks estate.
Who asked you to do that?
Uh, you did.
And a "thanks"
would have been nice.
Maybe one day
you're gonna be thanking me.
So, what do you want
with Eric Sacks?
My dad used to work for him.
He's the only person
that's gonna be able
to tell me whether
or not I'm crazy.
Crazy about what?
I don't need you
to laugh at me also.
Oh, come on, O'Neil.
This is
the Fenwick Express, it's a
judgment-free zone.
A cocoon of safety.
Promise?
I'm insulted that
you would suggest otherwise.
Ooh, 11 hours in the Ha'shi.
Are you sure none of you
want to tell me
where you were last night?
How you holding up, fellas?
Ah! I ain't breaking
if Donnie ain't breaking.
Experiencing intense nausea
but not breaking.
Guys? I'm in the zone!
There is literally nothing
that could break me right now!
Starting to break.
Of course, you've all tasted
the five-cheese pizza.
But this,
cheesemongers have speculated
of its existence
for centuries.
Da Vinci's
original masterpiece.
I submit to you...
...the 99-cheese pizza.
Oh!
It's not possible.
Mikey, it's a trap!
A pizza with that variety
of cheese
is a culinary impossibility!
Shall I list the ingredients?
No.
Cheddar...
Provolone...
Mikey, don't you do it!
Asiago...
Keep it together!
Taleggio...
I don't even
know what that is.
Mozzarella, of course.
All right, all right,
all right! We left the lair
because the Foot
were taking hostages
and we kicked
some serious butt,
and there was this girl
named April O'Neil
who took our picture,
but we took care of it.
Idiot.
Oh, no, my worst fears
have been realized.
Don't worry about it.
Donnie erased the picture!
We're not in danger.
No. It's April O'Neil
who is in danger!
Find the girl. Bring her here.
But,  sensei,
you said to not go...
Find the girl!
Find the girl.
That's what I told
Thompson and she fired me.
So they're aliens?
No, that's stupid.
They're reptiles.
They help people, I guess.
Heroes in the half-shell.
Okay.
Come on. It's not that crazy.
I... The animal kingdom
is full of...
I used to have a dog
that could moonwalk.
Thanks for the ride, Vern.
Yeah. No problem.
Nothing better than
dropping off a pretty girl
at a rich guy's house.
Hi, it's April O'Neil,
here to see Eric Sacks.
April's arrived
early this year.
I'm sorry to barge in on you
like this, Mr. Sacks.
No, no, no. Please, please.
Thank you.
I've been working on a story.
And I have this theory that
there are these vigilantes
that are fighting back
against the Foot.
I think you and my father
may have created them.
Uh, I'm not sure I...
Can you please tell me
everything that you know
about Project Renaissance?
Hmm.
Well, um, it was a dream.
A dream that died
with your father.
What if it isn't dead?
That's impossible.
We lost all our research
in the fire,
all our specimens, everything.
I've spent the last 15 years
trying to replicate
the results.
You didn't lose everything
in the fire.
This can't be real.
It is real.
I saw all four of them.
Do you really want to know
about Project Renaissance?
Yes.
Come with me.
I was born in Japan,
at a military base in Okinawa.
My father went to Vietnam.
Didn't come back.
I was an outsider
in a foreign land.
A freak.
I was a powerless
and helpless boy.
Until a local  sensei
took me under his wing.
And he saved me.
Taught me lessons that I
later shared with your father.
Ninth-century Japan.
An evil warlord
ruled the land.
He poisoned the water supply,
bringing on the dark ages.
Death and disease
and suffering ran rampant.
Not unlike the Foot Clan
and what they'd like to do
to our city.
Then one day, a hero arose.
A great alchemist
discovered the antidote
to the warlord's poison.
The cure-all
for his evil.
Your father and I were trying
to recreate that cure-all.
We developed a mutagen
capable of stimulating
self-repair
on a cellular level.
What were you
going to do with it?
Imagine New York City,
being victim
to a chemical attack.
This mutagen would be able
to reverse its effects.
It would save the city,
it would save the people.
Those test subjects,
those turtles...
Running in their blood
is the last
of this precious mutagen.
And up until
a few moments ago,
I thought we failed.
I thought they died
in the fire. How...
How could they have lived?
Because I saved them.
Of course you did.
April, the mutagen
possesses powers
beyond our wildest hopes.
Whatever resources you need,
I'm here.
Let's work together.
We'll find them.
The course of human history
may depend on it.
I'll show you out.
Bam! You've been hacked!
By Donatello. Remember me?
Turtle. Four eyes.
But enough about me.
We told you we'd find you.
Meet us here.
And come alone.
Or... Or else we're...
You shall be punished
and stuff.
Hello?
You told me to come here.
I didn't bring anyone with me.
I did exactly...
Okay! Are you April O'Neil?
Initiating retinal scan.
Scanning, scanning,
scanning, scanning.
Scan complete. It's her.
It's her. Guys, it's her!
Of course it's her, Donnie.
Hey.
Really glad you could make it.
Hey. There's someone important
we want to introduce you to,
but first...
Aw, yeah,
welcome to my crib, girl.
Where are we?
Hey,
it's our Fortress of Solitude.
Our Hogwarts.
Our Xavier Academy.
State-of-the-art WonderDome!
Ugh.
Are we in the sewer?
No.
- Technically, yes.
- Yeah.
Yeah, it's a sewer.
You brought us here, April.
Splinter?
How does she know his name?
Did you tell her his name?
Maybe she's clairvoyant.
Maybe she's a Jedi!
Come closer.
It's been a long time.
Mmm.
You always did have
your father's eyes.
I don't understand.
Don't be afraid.
All will be made clear.
This is crazy.
There's been a miracle.
The vigilantes who've been
causing us so much trouble?
They're the test subjects.
Those itty-bitty box turtles
that we thought
we lost in the fire?
They're alive,
Master Shredder.
And they've grown
into something
powerful.
It won't be easy to capture
them, but if we can,
we can finally
carry out the plan
that we had
all those years ago.
The city will be ours.
O'Neil's daughter
was the one who found them
and she will be the one who
will take us right to them.
There's the ping.
We've breached
the cloaking security.
Listen closely, April.
I don't remember a time
before living
in that laboratory.
That fateful night
started like any other.
Sacks gave us our injections.
Your father made sure
our vital signs were strong.
And you, as always,
provided us
with a special treat.
After the brothers
went to sleep,
I heard loud voices.
There was the smell of smoke.
Alarms sounded.
Your father
had discovered the truth
behind the man
he was working for.
He set fire to the lab.
His last breath was taken
trying to destroy
Shredder's plan.
I was terrified.
But then, you appeared.
And ushered us to safety.
I never had a voice then,
but I thank you now, April.
Mmm.
We wandered the sewers
until I found this place.
It was then that the mutagen
that was injected
into our blood
began to change us
in miraculous ways.
I saw how your father loved you
and I knew I had to show
that same love to the turtles.
I became their father
and they became my sons.
Like all children,
they were drawn
to the distractions
of popular culture.
They would want
to explore the world above.
They would be ridiculed.
They would need to learn
to protect themselves,
both mentally and physically.
Hey. Does anyone
want to play Buck-Buck?
Buck one!
Buck two!
Buck three!
Where you going, Raph?
Come on.
I can't do it by myself.
I need all four!
You're a Buck short.
Yeah, that sounds
stupid. Like you, Mikey!
That's why you're just
the hype man, bra.
- See these moves?
- Yeah, whatever, man.
And then I found a way.
First, I would teach myself
the ancient art of Ninjutsu.
Oh!
The brothers
followed my lead,
accelerating
at a wondrous rate!
Wassup, bra?
Want some of this?
I'm like a ghost!
I'm over here, now I'm over
here, bra. Like a shadow!
I'm a flame
shadow fire dragon!
Ow!
Their gift
was also their passion.
They lived,
breathed and dreamed
all things martial arts.
Then,
they were ready.
The katana,
most noble of all the blades.
It is the weapon of a leader.
Everything they are,
and everything
that they've become
was made possible
by the bravery that
you displayed
on that fateful night.
Dude.
I was just a little girl.
And you gave us freedom
where others
would have kept us in cages.
Wait a minute, Dad.
All these years you told us we
were rescued from the fire
by a great guardian spirit,
the  Hogo-sha.
That's right.
And this is the  Hogo-sha.
What?
My girlfriend's totally
the  Hogo-sha.
Ow.
Fortunately, our engineers
have been making
great progress
in refining the robotics
in your armor.
We're taking it
to the next level,
bridging the gap
between ancient tradition
and modern warfare.
Why did you bring me here?
To find out who you told
of our existence.
Nobody that believed me,
except for Eric Sacks.
Sacks.
Just as I feared.
Sacks is not a friend.
His soul has been poisoned
by the influence
of a dark master.
The Shredder.
Shredder practically
raised Sacks in Japan.
He's like a father to him.
Sacks will do anything
for his master.
Wait, wait.
Sacks and Shredder?
So, why aren't we out there
hunting them down?
Because, Raphael,
The Shredder
is a skilled warrior
whose cruelty
is ever-reaching!
And you are just teenagers.
The mutagen in your blood
is of great value to them.
Now that Sacks
has confirmation
that you are alive,
I fear they will bring
the fight to us.
Oh, no.
Stand by
to make entry. Let's move!
Go, go, go!
Perimeter infringe.
Breached! We have incoming!
Oh, no! Oh, no!
We got two breaches.
Fan room, weapons wall!
Mikey, flank right!
Donnie, on me!
We gotta go! Go, go!
Stand by to set charge.
Lock and load.
We're going on 10.
No live ammo. Tranqs only.
Take 'em alive!
No! Get back!
Donnie!
Engage!
Get him!
There they are!
Neutralize them!
They've got tranq darts!
Well, don't let them
hit your skin.
Let's go! Let's move!
Over there!
Tango at 12!
Wassup, bra? Oh, you think
you can handle this, huh?
I'm a snapping turtle, fool.
Snap, snap, snap!
I meant to do that!
I meant to do it!
We got a breach
in the fan room!
Raph! Get to the fan room!
Why are you always telling me
what to do?
Just go! Mikey, you gotta get
April out of here, now!
I got this!
April, come with me.
I got a safe place
for you to hide.
And if you get thirsty,
I got a secret stash of Orange
Crush behind the fridge.
Don't tell Raph.
Shredder.
All these years
I've been trying
to recreate the mutagen.
And you?
You just handed it to me.
You will not lay a hand
on my sons.
Your sons?
You think you're their father?
Very good, rat!
Sensei!
Donnie!
Hang on, Leo! Be right there!
You stupid little girl!
April!
Sensei!
No, my son, stay back!
Sensei! Dad!
Dad! What are you...
What are you doing?
Hide!
No!
Save yourselves!
Children, drop your weapons,
or your father will die.
No!
Where's the fourth?
He's dead.
Destroy this place.
Keep moving!
Stay strong.
Remember,
pain's only in the mind.
Move along! Go!
Troop, go!
Move! Move!
Splinter.
Sensei.
Master.
Let's get him
to the needle room.
Package is secured. En route.
In approximately 40 minutes.
Prepare the containment units.
Inside those turtles
is the most precious
compound on Earth,
mutagen.
And we will drain every last
ounce of their blood
to get it,
even if it kills them.
Get the first aid kit!
On the shelf!
Hurry. Hurry.
Raphael?
I'm here.
You must save your brothers.
Stop Shredder.
Sensei.
It's some kind of tracker.
It's Donatello!
Go, Raphael.
Let's go save my brothers.
We need a ride.
O'Neil!
Look, Vern,
I need you to meet me
at Cortlandt Alley
in 10 minutes, please.
Wait, why?
I can't talk to you about it
on the phone.
Just promise
you're gonna be there.
What do you mean, you can't
talk about... You called...
...me.
All right. Want me
to meet you right now?
I'll play your little game.
What's with the hat?
What is with the...
I don't know,
it's a buddy of mine's.
It's just a goof.
What do you want to do?
You wanna head downtown?
Eric Sacks is working with
the head of the Foot Clan.
They just kidnapped
the vigilante turtles
to take them
to the Sacks estate.
We need to go. Come on, Vern.
Right, right, right.
The turtles. I forgot.
This is getting
embarrassing. O'Neil,
we're both consenting adults.
We're both very good-looking.
You're better, probably.
That's up for debate.
But the point is, we don't
need to make up excuses
to hang out with each other.
What?
You want to spend more time
with me. I get it.
I would too.
We need to get to
the Sacks estate
right now, Vern. Come on!
"The Sacks estate
with the vigilante..."
What...
Drive!
You're a talking turtle.
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm a talking turtle
and you're a human nerd.
Now that we got that
out of the way, hit it.
I've never been accused
of being a nerd before, but...
I'm sorry...
How did you get in...
How did he get in the...
Oh, my.
Wow.
Unbelievable.
Let me look at you.
I'm a hard guy
to impress, but...
This is just...
Oh, my God.
Wow!
And we were gonna use rabbits!
Can you imagine that?
All we were trying to do
is create an antidote.
For what?
Say that again.
I want to hear your voice.
For what?
Wow.
Well, uh, we had this plan.
A plan that we're ready
to put back online today.
I'll show you. Karai, um...
Show them.
What?
Do you know my building,
Sacks Tower?
Got that great big
spire up on top?
That spire is filled...
...with tons
of chemical toxins.
No! No!
Bad stuff.
That kinda bad.
In a few hours,
Shredder is going to unleash
all that stuff
over the whole city.
The initial death toll
will shake world governments
to their core.
In 30 days,
the city of New York
will be a quarantine zone.
And that is where
my company comes in.
I'm going to save everyone
with the antidote
that is made from the mutagen
that is oozing
through your blood.
The government will then send
Sacks Industry a blank check
and I'm going to be rich.
Like, stupid rich.
Shredder will force this city
to live under our rule.
We will be gods.
Yeah,
I've thought about...
not becoming a ninja, but
I was doing a bunch of yoga
for like, 10 days
at one point, and, uh,
I pulled a hamstring.
There's the gate right there.
There it is.
Ram the gate.
"Ram the gate"?
This is Channel 6 property.
I said ram the gate!
All right,
everybody, strap in!
Oh, shit!
Go, go, go, go!
Follow me!
I'll take this canister
to New York
to withdraw the mutagen.
Make sure that
you drain all their blood.
Time to take a bite
out of the Big Apple.
Hey!
Get out of here!
Leo!
About time.
What the...
Raphael.
Glad you could join us.
The fourth cage is for you.
That's harsh, man.
The rat did not
teach you well!
Raphael!
You.
Focus on me.
Three... Four total turtles.
One's fighting
a robot samurai. Why not?
Donnie!
Adrenaline.
What?
All right. All right.
Adrenaline.
He's going to kill him.
Get up!
It's working.
I think we should move.
Oh! I feel really good right
now! I feel like running!
I feel like cleaning!
Who wants to clean the dojo?
I'll clean the dojo!
Endorphins! Endorphins!
We got to get Raph!
Raph! Raph!
Are you okay?
Are you dead? Are you okay?
Come on. Come on.
- Go where?
- Sacks Tower!
New York City! Times Square!
Shredder's going to
release a toxin!
It's gonna poison
the whole city!
And Sacks is gonna
sell the antidote!
That's in our blood!
So we've got
to get going now!
Good. Let's do it for  sensei.
Okay.
We're going!
Everybody calm down!
Look how calm I am!
We got to move.
Let's go!
Sacks is airborne!
Flight time to Manhattan,
19 minutes!
Get us out of here, Donnie!
Oh, my gosh, they have guns!
Get down!
Ha! Are you guys okay?
We're bulletproof.
Sweet!
Advance and engage!
Can you drive that truck?
Yeah!
We're on Raph. Ready?
Come on!
Everybody in the truck!
We gotta go, go, go! Move!
Vern, you know
how to drive this, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just got to
hotwire this thing, I guess.
Classic
blue wire/red wire situation.
Keys!
Yeah.
Keys are better.
Drive!
I'm on it!
That's all I need is a
backseat-driving
talking turtle!
- Let's go!
- Move!
- Jackal-One-Tango, on your 12!
-  Copy that.
I shouldn't have doubted you.
Sorry I didn't
stick up for you.
I can't believe that you're
not crazy! How crazy is that?
Target, 12 o'clock!
Where are we going, guys?
Donnie, what's the fastest
way back to Manhattan?
We just need
to stay on this road.
If we can get to
the maintenance hatch
at the bottom of the hill,
there's a sewer line
2.4 miles from here.
Mikey! Let them know up there!
I'm on it!
Oh, no.
Vern, go, go, go, go, go!
I'm on it!
Stop!
Vern, hit the brakes!
Wrong way! Wrong way!
Go around! Go, go, go!
Leo, move, move!
What?
Opposite,
opposite, opposite!
Oh, no!
How far off course are we?
Actually, we're on
a bit of a shortcut.
But we need
to keep going down.
Straight down.
Hey!
Just keep
going straight!
What's up, angel cakes?
Fire!
Guys, Leo's in trouble!
My shell's cracked.
Just tape it up.
Allow me to be
the bad-ass for once.
Hang on, Leo. Disengaging.
God, I've always wanted
to try this.
I got you, brother.
One car down, two to go.
Mikey!
All right, that's it.
I'll take it from here!
Whoo-hoo!
Raph, I'm driving!
Yeah!
Whoo-hoo!
O'Neil, what are you doing?
Yeah, that's good. Make sure
you're getting everything.
Vern!
O'Neil! Give me your arm!
Avalanche!
Whoa!
Come on,
Leo, wake up!
Yeah! If you wake up,
I promise to do
anything you say!
Guys! Shredder's chopper
is 20 miles
outside of New York City
airspace!
Thanks for
the traffic update, Donnie.
You doing sports
and weather next?
If you're gonna be
nasty about it
then I guess
you don't want to know
that there's a 500-foot
drop-off in 53 seconds!
Are you saying there's...
A cliff!
We gotta get April out
of there! Raph, heads up!
Don't forget that old guy!
Hi. Change of plans.
Oh, come on.
Guys, get down! Get down!
Twelve seconds
and we're going over!
Hey, Donnie,
do that fancy slingshot thing!
We got to take
Little Miss Sunshine out!
Batter up!
Grab on.
Mikey! Grab the cable!
I got it! I got it!
Hold on! Hold on!
Oh, no!
No, no, no!
Oh, no...
Poor Leo, April...
And that other guy.
They were so young,
so beautiful.
They ain't dead,
numb nuts.
Oh. Right on.
I hope you got a parachute
under that shell.
Hey, guys!
It's the maintenance hatch!
Our ticket home!
A little help, please!
Guys, we gotta
hustle. Shredder's over
New York City!
Sensei,
the mutagen is
four minutes out.
Moving forward as planned.
Please keep your arms and legs
inside the shell at all times.
Satellite imagery shows
Shredder's reached the top
of Sacks Tower.
If that's where he's releasing
the toxin from...
It's gonna
spread all over the city!
We need to...
...break a left!
We gotta find the elevators
and get up to the roof.
You guys get out of here.
Get to a safe distance.
No, no, we can go find Sacks
and get our hands on the
mutagen as a contingency plan,
just in case... You know.
Thanks for
the vote of confidence.
If we don't make it back,
bring the mutagen to Splinter.
It can save his life.
Sacks's laboratory's
on the 36th floor.
I've already disabled
the security system.
Oh, and, uh...
Good luck!
If I don't return,
remember me, April.
You can always find me
in here.
You're a complicated chick.
Yeah.
Elevator's just
around this corner!
All right, guys, listen up.
We stick to my plan
and we won't fail.
Fan out
in three, two, one.
Whoa.
Not the elevator.
Nope.
The first vial
is filling with antidote now.
Initiating
the toxin release procedure.
MC Mikey.
MC
Ready, stance!
Hey, Mikey, remember that
thing you used to say
when we were kids?
You made me promise
never to say it again.
Forget about that.
Still got one in the tank?
I've been
holding it in for years.
Guys, we need a plan!
Cowabunga!
Leo!
Yeah, we got a 10-10.
Debris falling
from the building.
Come on.
I got this, guys!
I'll take him!
Come on!
Oh, no, you don't!
Seriously,
you two...
You're adorable, really.
I could just
pinch your cheeks!
Ugh, guys,
he's coming, he's coming!
Guys!
Donnie!
Come on, come on!
Hold on, Leo!
I understand a girl
with dead daddy issues.
I do. But you're not
gonna stop me.
This is history
repeating itself.
Your father walked in on me,
April, just like you did.
It took a few less bullets
to take him down, though.
You killed my father.
Move! Move!
Go, go, go!
Come on, guys!
Got you!
Enough. The lesson is over.
Ugh! We're getting
our asses kicked out there.
We only got 50 more seconds
before the toxin's released.
Hey.
Who wants to play Buck-Buck?
Buck-Buck?
What?
Buck-Buck. Tony-on-a-Pony.
Some people call it
Johnnie-on-a-Rock.
Wait.
Yeah.
Let's play Buck-Buck.
But why would we...
No.
We do what Leo says.
Lead the way.
O'Neil!
Argh!
Hmm.
Oh!
Cowabunga.
Are you okay?
Look, just go get some help
and take the mutagen with you.
Just go. Go!
No!
Just another day in the life
of a man of action.
Ow. No, I'm not getting up.
You know
how to use this thing?
It's a simple
command-line interface.
No one's used this code
in 15 years.
I mean,
I've read about it online.
But these kind of things
take time.
Thinking there was no way
I'd ever be in a position
where the fate
of an entire city...
I'll buy you some time.
Toxin disbursement
in five, four,
three,
two...
Bam! System disabled!
Who wants Italian?
I'm buying!
Tiramisu for everybody! Ah!
Ah.
Fall in!
Hold on! Hold it! Hold it!
If the spire falls and the
toxin makes ground impact,
it'll contaminate
a 10-block radius!
What are the odds of us
stopping that from happening?
Uh, 0.00000000003%!
I'll take it.
Nobody moves, no matter what.
But, Leo...
I said nobody moves!
Leo, I'm letting go!
Ah!
Shredder!
This is all that's left!
Little girl.
That belongs to me.
Hold on! Hold on! Hold it!
Get back! All the way back!
April!
Come on, guys!
Ah!
April!
Got you, Raph!
Hold on! Hold on! April!
I got you.
Swing me towards him!
Do it!
Leo!
That's my girl.
I think this is it, guys!
Does anyone have anything
they want to say?
Donnie?
I'm the one
who licks the icing
off the Pop-Tarts
every morning
and puts them back in the box.
No, no, no, no!
I so did not understand
the ending of  Lost.
Raph?
I just, uh...
If this is
our last moment together,
I just want you guys
to know I'm sorry.
I'm sorry
I was so hard on you.
Every time I pushed you,
I... I threatened you,
I yelled at you, I pushed you
beyond your limits,
it was because
I believe in you!
I believe in each
one of you!
I believe in your spirit
and your intelligence
and your potential.
And every time I talked
about walking away,
it was because I was scared!
I just didn't think
I was good enough
to stand next to you
and call you brothers
and say to you
I love you!
I love you guys so much!
Raph?
We made it.
Are you crying?
No, ding-dong. It's just
a little dusty out here.
Okay, the mutagen is now
entering his bloodstream.
Master Splinter?
Nothing's happening.
Why isn't it working yet?
Mikey...
Huh?
Mikey, come closer.
What did he say?
He said, "Please get
your knee off my chest."
Sensei!
You're alive!
It worked!
I'm sorry.
This was all my fault.
You were right.
We weren't ready.
No.
It was I who wasn't ready
to let you go.
All you needed was to discover
that your true power lies
in believing in one another.
There she is.
New York's secret weapon.
How's your arm, Vern?
Well, it wouldn't be
much use in a fight.
Not that I was
much use before, but...
Did you get a new car?
Yeah.
You're looking
at the new Fenwick Express.
Pretty sweet, huh?
Kind of an upgrade.
I figured I'd need new wheels
after my old
work vehicle went boom.
Yeah, Channel 6 gave it to me.
They said
don't put a scratch on it,
but, like, lightning's going
to strike twice?
So, is that why
you called me here,
to talk about your new car?
I know that you're not exactly
a fancy restaurant
kind of girl, so I figured
a creepy underpass
in an abandoned neighborhood
in the middle of the night
was more your speed.
I wanted you
to be comfortable.
DJ Mikey in the house!
What are you guys doing here?
We figured we owed you a
thanks for keeping our secret.
You had a lot to gain
from telling people about us,
but you had our backs.
Yeah, 'cause that's what
family's for, Raph.
So you guys are driving now?
Yeah, man.
I pimped this bad boy out.
Got a 42-inch plasma with the
NBA package,
shave ice machine,
7.1 digital surround sound.
Check the bass, bra.
Uh-oh.
Ooh.
My bad. I'm still
figuring out the buttons.
That was my new
Fenwick Express!
I just... I just got that.
We better get out of here.
Want a ride home?
You know what? I think
we're gonna take the subway.
We're going
to take the subway.
You sure?
I got a real nice song
that's all cued up.
- It's special, girl.
- No, don't.
- For us.
- Come on, Mikey.
No, no, no,
Mikey, you promised.
¶ Imagine me and you
I do
¶ I think about you
day and night
It's only right
¶ To think about... ¶
I'm making
really good headway!
Shut up, Mikey!
¶ I can't see me
loving nobody but you
¶ For all my life
¶ When you're with me, baby
¶ The skies'll be blue
For all my life! ¶